<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<eula xmlns="http://www.oxygenxml.com/legal-document" revisionDate="2012-11-06+02:00">
    <info>
        <title>oXygen XML Editor SDK License Agreement</title>
    </info>
    <xi:include href="EULA_OXYGEN.xml" xpointer="important"
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
    <section>
        <title>DEFINITION</title>
        <list numeration="alpha">
            <item> "Syncro" means Syncro Soft S.R.L.</item>
            <item>"Oxygen" means the specific software products for editing and authoring XML
                documents, that Syncro have developed as featured on http://www.oxygenxml.com
                website. Oxygen includes any new releases, upgrades, updates and on-line or
                electronic documentation.</item>
            <item>"Licensee" (or "You") means the individual who or entity that accepted and agreed
                to be bound by the terms and conditions of this License.</item>
            <item>An "Add-on" means a software program or a custom configuration framework that
                works within Oxygen (it cannot operate on its own). Oxygen supports Add-ons to
                enable third-party developers to create specific abilities which extend Oxygen
                features. Examples of such Add-ons are: plug-ins, new frameworks for XML document
                types, customization of an Oxygen framework for a default document type (DITA,
                DocBook, TEI, etc.) or extensions to access Oxygen XML Eclipse plug-in features from
                your own Eclipse plug-in.</item>
            <item>"Software" means the Oxygen XML Software Development Kit (SDK) which enables you
                to develop Add-ons or Applications (as defined in section
                    <?oxy_insert_start author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034203+0200"?><ref
                    refId="grants"
                /><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034200+0200" content="2.1"?>).
                The Software is comprised of libraries, source code, APIs, sample code and online or
                electronic documentation.</item>
        </list>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="licenseGrants">
        <title>LICENSE GRANTS</title>
        <item xml:id="grants">Subject to all the terms and conditions set forth in this Agreement,
            Syncro hereby grants You a limited, non-exclusive, revocable, non-sublicensable and
            non-transferable license to:<list numeration="alpha">
                <item>Install a reasonable number of copies of the Software on computers owned or
                    controlled by you, to be used internally by you or your authorized users for the
                    sole purpose of internal evaluation, testing and "Development Activity" in
                    strict compliance with the terms stated below. For the purpose of this
                    Agreement, "Development Activity" means the activity to: <list
                        numeration="alpha">
                        <item>Develop Add-ons designed to function within Oxygen. A license for
                            deploying such Add-ons to end-users is granted royalty fee, under your
                            own terms and conditions.</item>
                        <item>Integrate the Software with any custom software application that you
                            have developed ("Application") as more explicitly defined in section
                                <?oxy_insert_start author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034402+0200"?><ref
                                refId="ac-enduserapp"
                            /><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034359+0200" content="3.2"?>.The
                            part of the Software that is integrated in Application is defined as
                            "Author Component" and a license for deploying such Application to
                            end-users is granted according to section
                                <?oxy_insert_start author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034518+0200"?><ref
                                refId="authorComponent"
                            /><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034446+0200" content="3 (&quot;Author Component &quot;)"?>.</item>
                    </list></item>
                <item>You may make one copy of the Software in machine-readable form for backup
                    purposes only. The backup copy must include all copyright information contained
                    on the original.</item>
            </list></item>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="authorComponent">
        <title>AUTHOR COMPONENT </title>
        <item>If you intend to integrate Author Component into your Application, you must register
            to Syncro and request an Author Component Development Key that will enable you to use
            the Software for free for twelve (12) months after installation ("Development Period")
            for Development Activity only. The Development Period may be extended for successive
            terms of one year subject to written request to Syncro. The Software contains a feature
            that will automatically disable it at the end of Development Period. Syncro will have no
            liability to you if this feature disables the Software. </item>
        <item xml:id="ac-enduserapp">The Application developed by You must be an "end user
            application." An "end user application" is a specific application program that is
            licensed to a person or company for personal or business use and not with a view toward
            redistributing the application or any part of the application, and may be either an
            application that is used by Licensee internally, or an application that is commercially
            distributed to end users for their use. An end user of an Application may not modify or
            redistribute the Application and may not copy it (other than for archival purposes).
            Licensee's license agreement covering the Application must contain restrictions
            prohibiting redistribution, modification and copying of the Application. You agree to
            defend, indemnify and hold harmless Syncro, and its officers, directors, employees,
            agents and representatives, from or in connection with damages, liabilities, costs and
            expenses (including reasonable attorneys' fees) incurred by Syncro on account of you not
            including these terms in any of your customer license agreements. </item>
        <item>Deployment license grant. Subject to all the terms and conditions set forth in this
            Agreement, including without limitation, the payment of the runtime licensing fees
            described in section
                <?oxy_insert_start author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034616+0200"?><ref
                refId="authorComponent"
            /><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034613+0200" content="3"?>
            hereof, Syncro hereby grants You a non-exclusive, non-transferable, worldwide license to
            reproduce exact copies of the Author Component and include such files in the
            Application, and to deploy the Application on your owned and controlled computers and
            networks for use by your employees, contractors and affiliates and/or to commercially
            distribute the Application, directly and through customary distribution channels, to end
            users for their use without further distribution. You must purchase a runtime license
            for each deployment of Application. Such licenses are available only from Syncro and
            Syncro distributors. For purposes hereof, a "Deployment of Application" includes
            Name-User Deployments and Concurrent Deployments as hereinafter defined:<list
                numeration="alpha">
                <item>Named or Concurrent Oxygen Licenses - If the Application will be used by You
                    internally,You will have the option to buy or use already bought regular Oxygen
                    software licenses that will enable (more than the normal usage conferred by the
                    Oxygen license) the runtime usage of the Author Component as it was integrated
                    into the Application.</item>
                <item>Author Component Named-User Deployment. An "Author Component Named-user
                    Deployment" means installation of the Application by You and/or your customers
                    for use by a single named user. The sharing of the Named-user Deployment License
                    by more than one individual is expressly prohibited.</item>
                <item>Author Component Concurrent Deployment. An "Author Component Concurrent
                    Deployment" means that
                    <?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121109T105723+0200"?>You have
                    built a method of concurrency control into the Application so that
                    <?oxy_insert_end?>the number of end users belonging to one of your customers
                    accessing the Application at any one time may not exceed the number of
                    concurrent deployment licenses obtained by You for that customer. For each of
                    your customers You are required to purchase a separate Component Concurrent
                    Deployment
                    license.<?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121113T085919+0200"?>
                    Concurrent Deployment Licenses are available in perpetual or subscription term
                    <?oxy_custom_start type="oxy_content_highlight" color="255,255,0"?>(as described
                    in section
                        <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034706+0200"?><ref
                        refId="licenseRestrictions"
                    /><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034704+0200" content="4"?><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121113T085919+0200"?>)<?oxy_custom_end?><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="georgebina" timestamp="20130122T103734+0200"?>.<?oxy_insert_end?></item>
                <item>Author Component Subscription Deployment. If You licensed the Author Component
                    on a subscription basis, the end-user right to access the Author Component
                    integrated into your Application is limited to the subscription period that
                    shall be indicated in your accepted order.
                    <?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121106T130037+0200"?>You agree
                    to take such steps as are appropriate to ensure that after the expiration of the
                    subscription period, the end-user is no longer entitled to use or access the
                    Author Component.<?oxy_insert_end?></item>
                <?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121107T151237+0200"?>
                <item>Author Component Applet License. Allows Application built with Software to be
                    deployed to an application server used to directly
                    deploy<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T171014+0200"?>
                    the<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121107T151237+0200"?>
                    Application to end-users to be used from a web-browser. In this case You have to
                    build an access control mechanism so that each end-user that
                    access<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T171042+0200"?>es<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121107T151237+0200"?>
                    the Application from a web-browser should be authenticated and logged on. The
                    royalty for this license is
                    <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T171209+0200" content="function of"?><?oxy_insert_start author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T171210+0200"?>directly
                    proportional
                    with<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121107T151237+0200"?>
                    the number of unique named users that
                    <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T171229+0200" content="used"?><?oxy_insert_start author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T171229+0200"?>accessed<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121107T151237+0200"?>
                    the Application during one month. </item>
                <?oxy_insert_end?>
            </list></item>
        <item>Evaluation and Demo Versions. If the Application is sold commercially by You, then You
            may have an evaluation version of the Application that You make available free of charge
            to prospects, provided the evaluation version expires within 30 days of a prospect's
            installation of the evaluation version, and provided it is covered by an evaluation
            license agreement that provides that the prospect may only use it for evaluation
            purposes. In addition, You may issue a reasonable number of demonstration copies of the
            Application to your sales and support staff, for their use in connection with selling
            and supporting the Application. No runtime license fees will be payable for evaluation
            and demo versions of the Application deployed in accordance with this paragraph. </item>
        <?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121108T145039+0200"?>
        <item> Prepayment of License Fees. Initially, prepayment is required for all deployment
            license orders and a separate Deployment License Key will be
            <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T171406+0200" content="generated"?><?oxy_insert_start author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T171406+0200"?>provided<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121108T145039+0200"?>
            by Syncro for each order to be embedded into the Application to authenticate licensed
            copies of the Author Component. If You are later approved by Syncro for "Monthly
            Reporting and Payment" (see section
                <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034814+0200"?><ref
                refId="monthlyReporting"
            /><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034813+0200" content="3.6"?><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121108T145039+0200"?>),
            Syncro will <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T171455+0200" content="generate"?><?oxy_insert_start author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T171455+0200"?>provide<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121108T145039+0200"?>
            <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T171458+0200" content="for "?><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121108T145039+0200"?>You
            a Runtime Deployment License Key that can be embedded into your Application and used for
            any of Your
            customers<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T172238+0200"?>,
            <?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T172236+0200" content="."?><?oxy_insert_start author="Bogdan" timestamp="20121115T172244+0200"?>as
            long as Deployments are reported and paid in a timely
            manner.<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121108T145039+0200"?></item>
        <?oxy_insert_end?>
        <item xml:id="monthlyReporting"
            ><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121109T103248+0200"?>If You are
            approved by Syncro for "Monthly Reporting and Payment"<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="stefan" timestamp="20121115T165125+0200" content="Reporting and Payment. "?><?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20121115T165126+0200"?>
            <?oxy_insert_end?>You agree to maintain full, clear and accurate records as to all
            Deployments of the Application. If You are commercially distributing the Application
            through distributors or resellers, You will ensure that your distributors and resellers
            maintain adequate records to reflect all licenses in the Application that are sold or
            otherwise distributed by such parties. Syncro will send You a monthly deployment report
            form to complete at the end of each month and You will submit the report to Syncro,
            within ten (10) days of the close of each calendar month, setting forth the number of
            Deployments of Application, and the type of Deployment made during such month. If
            Licensee has new Deployments for the month, Licensee will pay Syncro the applicable
            runtime license fee. Syncro shall have the right, no more than once during any calendar
            year, to have an independent certified public accountant inspect the relevant records of
            Licensee on thirty (30) days notice and during regular business hours to verify the
            reports and payments required to be made hereunder. Should an underpayment in excess of
            five percent (5%) be discovered, You shall pay the cost of the audit. If You are more
            than thirty (30) days late with any payment of amount due hereunder, interest will
            accrue from the date due until paid at the lesser of (i) 1.5% per month or (ii) the
            maximum rate of interest permitted by law. All amounts due hereunder are based on United
            States currency. </item>
        <item>Author Component Support and Maintenance Pack.<list numeration="numeric">
                <item>A Support and Maintenance Pack ("SMP") is a time-limited right for Author
                    Component technical support, updates, and upgrades, which you may elect to
                    purchase in addition to the corresponding Deployment of Application for your
                    end-user. Technical support only covers issues or questions resulting directly
                    out of the operation of the Author Component. Syncro will not provide you or
                    your end-user with generic consultation, assistance, or advice under any other
                    circumstances.</item>
                <item>If you redeploy the Application with the new major version of the Author
                    Component and if your end-user's Author Component SMP is still in force, he is
                    entitled to this release of the Application, with no additional fee. If you do
                    not purchase SMP for your end-user, he will not be entitled to this release of
                    the Application unless the Author Component update or upgrade will be provided
                    free of charge by Syncro, under certain circumstances, or you will buy an
                    Application Component upgrade for that end-user.</item>
                <item>If you licensed Author Component Subscription Deployment, SMP is included in
                    the applicable subscription fee, and is valid for the entire subscription
                    period.</item>
                <item> For end-users that purchase or already own multiple Deployment of Application
                    licenses, an SMP must be purchased for each license.</item>
            </list></item>
        <item>Certain rights are not granted under this Agreement, but may be available under a
            separate agreement. Contact Syncro (support@oxygenxml.com) if you would like to sign a
            Value Added Reseller agreement.</item>
    </section>
    <section xml:id="licenseRestrictions">
        <title>LICENSE RESTRICTIONS</title>
        <item>The license granted under this Agreement is expressly conditioned upon your compliance
            with all the terms and conditions of this Agreement. Restrictions regarding your use of
            the Software are as follows:<list numeration="alpha">
                <item>You may only integrate Author Component if you registered to Syncro for an
                    Author Component Development Key. You must ensure that the Author Component
                    Deployment license key will not be deployed to end-users or seen in any way when
                    used in Application binary code. </item>
                <item>You may not use, copy, rent, lease, sell, sub-license, assign or otherwise
                    transfer the Software except as expressly provided for in this Agreement.</item>
                <item>You may not modify, port, adapt or translate the Software. You may not reverse
                    engineer, decompile, disassemble or otherwise attempt to discover the source
                    code of the Software.</item>
                <item>You may not expose the API (application program interface) provided by
                    Software to your end users and You may not use or call any classes or methods
                    that are not documented as part of the API.</item>
                <item>You may not use the SDK to develop and market an Add-on or Application which
                    consists of a development kit, a component, or an software product liable to
                    directly compete with Oxygen. </item>
                <item>You may only distribute, use or sub-license the Application developed using
                    the Software if You purchase a Runtime (Deployment) license, as described in
                    Section
                        <?oxy_insert_start author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034910+0200"?><ref
                        refId="licenseGrants"
                    /><?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="georgebina" timestamp="20130125T034907+0200" content="2"?>.</item>
                <item>You agree that you will not use the Software to create, develop an Add-on or
                    Application which: <list numeration="alpha">
                        <item>contains any spyware, malware, virus, worm, Trojan horse, or other
                            malicious or harmful code that are intended to damage, detrimentally
                            interfere with, surreptitiously intercept or expropriate any system,
                            data or personal information; </item>
                        <item>when used in the manner in which it is intended, violates any material
                            law, statute, ordinance or regulation (including without limitation the
                            laws and regulations governing export control, unfair competition, anti
                            discrimination, or false advertising).</item>
                    </list></item>
                <item>You shall not make any statements that your Add-on or Application is
                    "certified", or that its performance is guaranteed by Syncro. You shall not make
                    any statements implying that You are a Syncro "development partner" or that You
                    have a relationship with Syncro, except for any relationship as Syncro may
                    expressly acknowledge in writing. </item>
            </list></item>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>DEMONSTRATION COPY</title>
        <item>Syncro may, without obligation, at your request, promote your Add-ons or Application
            ("Customization") on Syncro website or in other marketing materials. You hereby grant to
            Syncro a non-exclusive, royalty-free license to use your trademarks associated with for
            Syncro use in connection with Syncro promotion, if any, of such Customization. At Syncro
            request, Syncro may become a reseller of the Customization on terms mutually agreeable
            to You and Syncro.</item>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>OWNERSHIP AND INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS</title>
        <item>The items in the Software are the intellectual property of Syncro and its suppliers
            and are protected by United States copyright and patent law, international treaty
            provisions and applicable laws of the country in which it is being used. You agree to
            protect all copyright and other ownership interests of Syncro and/or its suppliers in
            the Software supplied under this Agreement. You agree that all copies of the items in
            the Software, reproduced for any reason by You, contain the same copyright notices, and
            other proprietary notices as appropriate, as appear on or in the master items delivered
            by Syncro in the Software. Syncro and/or its suppliers retain title and ownership of the
            items in the Software, and all subsequent copies.</item>
        <item>Except as stated herein, this Agreement does not grant You any rights to patents,
            copyrights, trade secrets, trademarks, or any other rights in respect to the items in
            the Software, and all rights not expressly granted are reserved by Syncro and its
            suppliers.</item>
        <item>You may, from time to time, voluntarily elect to provide suggestions, comments and
            other feedback ("Feedback") to Syncro with respect to the Software. Syncro may, in
            connection with any of its products, services, specifications or technologies, freely
            use, copy, disclose, license, distribute and exploit any Feedback in any manner without
            any obligation or restriction based on intellectual property rights or otherwise. Syncro
            shall retain ownership of any Feedback. You shall not provide any Feedback subject to
            any terms that would impose any obligation on Syncro. </item>
        <item>Nothing in this Agreement shall be deemed to preclude Syncro from entering into
            agreements with or otherwise engaging other developers who may develop a similar
            Application or Add-on.</item>
    </section>
    <xi:include href="EULA_OXYGEN.xml" xpointer="patent_and_copyright_indemnity"
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
    <xi:include href="EULA_OXYGEN.xml" xpointer="warranties"
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
    <section>
        <title>TECHNICAL SUPPORT</title>
        <item>Syncro shall make available to You maintenance releases and updates to Software, as
            they become available as part of the maintenance and support service for Oxygen.
            Technical support services include telephone, web and/or email clarifications of the
            functions and features of the Software to assist You in developing your Add-on or
            Application. Any technical support that may be provided by Syncro shall be provided
            without warranties of any kind, unless separately agreed in writing between the
            parties.</item>
        <item>You shall be solely responsible for providing, and agree that you will provide,
            customer, technical, and help desk support to your end users of the Application or
            Add-on.</item>
    </section>
    <xi:include href="EULA_OXYGEN.xml" xpointer="liability"
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
    <xi:include href="EULA_OXYGEN.xml" xpointer="high_risk_activities"
        xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
    <section>
        <title>THIRD PARTY SOFTWARE</title>
        <item>The Software includes certain runtime libraries and files intended for duplication and
            distribution by You within the Application to the end-user of Application
            ("Redistributables").These Redistributables may require additional terms and conditions.
            Such required Redistributables notices and/or additional terms and conditions are
            located at http://www.oxygenxml.com/thirdparty/index.html and are made a part of and
            incorporated by reference into this Agreement. By accepting this Agreement, You are also
            accepting the additional terms and conditions, if any, forth therein.</item>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>TERM AND TERMINATION</title>
        <item> You may terminate this Agreement at any time by removing the Software from the
            computers on which you had install it. Upon any termination of this Agreement, you shall
            immediately discontinue use of the Software and destroy all copies of the Software. </item>
        <item>If you are using an Application Component Development Key, this Agreement will
            terminate at the end of Development Period unless extended by Syncro consent.</item>
        <item>Syncro may terminate the Agreement immediately, without judicial intervention, if You
            fail to comply with any term of this License Agreement. Upon such termination, You shall
            cease using the Software and cease using or distributing the Add-on or Application
            containing the Software. Termination will not affect properly granted end user licenses
            of the Add-on or Application distributed by You prior to termination.</item>
    </section>
    <xi:include href="EULA_OXYGEN.xml" xpointer="export" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
    <xi:include href="EULA_OXYGEN.xml" xpointer="general" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"/>
</eula>
<?oxy_options track_changes="on"?>