<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<addendum xmlns="http://www.oxygenxml.com/legal-document"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xml:id="addendum"
    range="CLASS DEPARTMENTAL SITE">
    <info>
        <title>oXygen XML Editor <phrase edition="ACADEMIC">Academic</phrase><phrase
                edition="PROFESSIONAL">Professional</phrase>
            <phrase edition="ENTERPRISE">Enterprise</phrase><phrase range="CLASS"
                >Classroom</phrase><phrase range="DEPARTMENTAL">Departmental</phrase><phrase
                range="SITE">Site</phrase> License Agreement - Addendum</title>
    </info>
    <important>THIS IS AN
        ADDENDUM<?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20120620T142100+0300"?> (THE
        "ADDENDUM")<?oxy_insert_end?> TO OXYGEN XML EDITOR END USER LICENSE AGREEMENT (THE
        &quot;AGREEMENT&quot;), AND THE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF THIS ADDENDUM ARE INCORPORATED
        THEREIN. EACH CAPITALIZED TERM USED HEREIN AND NOT DEFINED HEREIN SHALL HAVE THE MEANING
        ASCRIBED TO IT IN THE AGREEMENT.</important>
    <section>
        <title>Scope</title>
        <item>The provisions of this <phrase range="CLASS">Classroom</phrase><phrase
                range="DEPARTMENTAL">Departmental</phrase><phrase range="SITE">Site</phrase> License
            apply to the oXygen XML <phrase edition="ACADEMIC">Academic</phrase><phrase
                edition="PROFESSIONAL">Professional</phrase><phrase edition="ENTERPRISE"
                >Enterprise</phrase> Edition. In the event of a conflict between the provisions of
            this Addendum and the Agreement,
            the<?oxy_delete author="stefan" timestamp="20120620T142147+0300" content="se"?> Addendum
            provisions shall apply.</item>
    </section>
    <section range="CLASS">
        <title>Installation and use</title>
        <item>You may: <list numeration="alpha">
                <item>Use the Software for non-commercial classroom teaching educational services.
                    You certify that use is directly related to classroom teaching that use is
                    strictly for noncommercial purposes.</item>
                <item>Install the Software on each computer within the classroom in which You teach
                    only, regardless of how many students You teach in the classroom on up to 25
                    computers (seats).</item>
                <item>Install the Software on a personal computer used by the individual student
                    covered by this license at home for instructional preparation only.</item>
                <item>Individual teachers covered by this license are entitled to a free Home
                    Edition license.</item>
            </list>
        </item>
    </section>
    <section range="DEPARTMENTAL">
        <title>Installation and use</title>
        <item>You may:<list numeration="alpha">
                <item>Use the Software solely in non-commercial departmental teaching and research
                    programs. You are permitted to distribute copies of the Software to faculty
                    members, staff, and students, officers, employees ("Recipients") within the
                    licensed department. Recipients may not keep or use the Software when they
                    finish their courses or leave the department. </item>
                <item>Install the Software on any computer that is in regular use at the facilities
                    of the Department. All copies of the Software must be removed from each computer
                    that is taken out of regular use at the facilities of the Department. </item>
                <item>Install the Software on a personal computer used by the Recipient covered by
                    this license at home for instructional preparation only. </item>
                <item>Individual teachers covered by this license are entitled to a free Home
                    Edition license.</item>
            </list></item>
    </section>
    <section range="SITE">
        <title>Installation and use</title>
        <item>You may: <list numeration="alpha">
                <item>Install the Software on any computer that is located at any of Your
                    facilit<?oxy_insert_start author="stefan" timestamp="20120620T142331+0300"?>ies<?oxy_insert_end?><?oxy_delete author="stefan" timestamp="20120620T142333+0300" content="y"?>
                    within a 3 mile radius around Your address (the "Site Location"). All copies of
                    the Software must be removed from each computer that is taken out of regular use
                    at the facilities of the Site Location. </item>
                <item><phrase edition="ACADEMIC">Use the Software solely in non-commercial teaching
                        and research programs.</phrase> You are permitted to distribute copies of
                    the Software to the members, staff, and <phrase edition="ACADEMIC">students,
                        officers,</phrase> employees ("Recipients") within the licensed Site
                    Location. Recipients may not keep or use the Software when they finish their
                    courses or leave the Site Location. </item>
                <item edition="ACADEMIC">Install the Software on a personal computer used by the
                    Recipient covered by this license at home for instructional preparation
                    only.</item>
                <item edition="ACADEMIC"> Individual teachers covered by this license are entitled
                    to a free Home Edition license.</item>
            </list></item>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Maintenance pack.</title>
        <item>First year Maintenance Pack is included.</item>
    </section>
    <section>
        <title>Assignment.</title>
        <list numeration="alpha">
            <item><phrase range="CLASS">Classroom</phrase><phrase range="DEPARTMENTAL"
                    >Departmental</phrase><phrase range="SITE">Site</phrase> license is
                nontransferable. You may not transfer ownership of this license to anyone else. You
                may not distribute copies to personnel in other <phrase range="CLASS"
                    >classrooms</phrase><phrase range="DEPARTMENTAL">departments or
                    institutions</phrase><phrase range="SITE">Site Locations</phrase>.</item>
            <item edition="ACADEMIC">When schools or educational institutions acquire the <phrase
                    range="CLASS">Classroom</phrase><phrase range="DEPARTMENTAL"
                    >Departmental</phrase><phrase range="SITE">Site</phrase> License, the Software
                can only be installed to the computers in one <phrase range="DEPARTMENTAL"
                    >department</phrase><phrase range="SITE">Site Location</phrase><phrase
                    range="CLASS">classroom at a time and previous installations should be
                    uninstalled</phrase>.</item>
        </list>
    </section>
</addendum>

